

# Sylvain Doignon

Relocating to Greater London  $\Box$  + 33 6 23 54 16 56 ☑ sylvain@doignon.fr in sylvain-doignon

## Senior DevSecOps Lead & Technology Enthusiast

Summary: Senior DevSecOps Lead with 10+ years of experience delivering secure, scalable infrastructure and developer platforms, with full ownership of delivery, reliability, monitoring, and alerting. Experienced in leading small teams and working across international teams and external partners. Comfortable collaborating with stakeholders to align infrastructure with business goals. Relocating to Greater London and seeking a remote-first role, open to occasional in-person collaboration.

## **Experience**

American Express GBT Remote DevSecOps Lead, Neo1

2022 - Present

- o Directed all DevSecOps operations: infrastructure, PCI-DSS compliance, coordination across internal teams and partners.
- Led a small international team of engineers, receiving mentorship to strengthen my management and leadership skills.
- Scaled infrastructure and tooling to support product growth from startup scale to a 40 person team.
- O Designed and implemented innovative security tools and automation solutions.

**KDS** Remote / Paris / London 2017 - 2022 DevSecOps Engineer, Neo1

Created an AWS native, secure and scalable infrastructure for a new PCI-DSS compliant SaaS SME spend-management app.

Migrated all code, processes and workflows from GitLab to GitHub. TODO.

Société Générale Paris / Luxembourg 2014 - 2017

DevOps Engineer, Apprenticeship, Corporate & Investment Banking

Administered Linux systems and automated various accounts, VMs and logs processes where speed and reliability mattered.

Developed APIs & Web apps as a full-stack developer to help expose those tools internally.

#### Education

#### University of Technology of Compiègne (UTC), part of Sorbonne Universités

Compiègne

Master degree in Computer Sciences & Engineering Infrastructure & Systems specialization

2014 - 2017

#### University of Bordeaux Montaigne

**Bordeaux** 

Technical degree (DUT) in System & Network Services

2012 - 2014

Graduation with honors

## Skills

Cloud & DevOps: Extensive Hands-On AWS; Compute, Storage, IAM, Networking, CDN, Serverless, Database, Monitoring & Alerting (CloudWatch & ELK); Infrastructure as Code; CI/CD (GitHub, GitLab); Linux, Docker, Git, Shell Scripting; Developer Tooling & Support Scripts; Microservices architecture; Technical & Compliance Documentation.

**Development**: Python, JavaScript, Go, AWK.

Web: In-depth knowledge of web technologies across all layers, from user interaction to servers, including HTTP, browser-server architecture, web stacks, API design, RESTful services, and protocol-level behavior (TCP/IP, DNS, SSL/TLS).

Security: Designed secure systems with PCI-DSS compliance in mind, proactively preparing for audits and penetration tests. Addressed auditor queries, provided evidence, and remediated findings. Investigated and resolved security vulnerabilities from actual threats. Experienced with security tools like Prisma Cloud, Wiz, Qualys, etc.

## **Personal Skills**

Constant Learner: I make learning a part of my daily routine with a particular passion for engineering topics in all their forms. I also have a keen interest in world economics, avid reader of the Financial Times.

IT News: For 15 years, I've stayed up-to-date with industry trends through my daily curated RSS feed.

Solution-oriented: I thrive on finding practical solutions to a wide range of problems, both IT-related and beyond.

#### Languages

English: Full professional proficiency. Lived and worked in London.

TOEIC 970/990

French: Native Language.

### **Miscellaneous**

Hobbies: Engineering, World Economics, UK culture, Hardware, Smart Home, Gardening. Family IT support: yes, Mom, I'll fix it again.

Sports: Rock climbing and biking with my dog.